sha la la some day in the future
sha la la itsuka kitto
I will for sure hold it in my hand
boku wa te ni suru nda
it will softly set ablaze
hakanaki mune ni sotto
a light in my empty heart
hikari moeteyuke
the "impulses" that makes you want to meet it
aitaku naru no shoudou
the "innocence" that makes you want to cry
nakitaku naru no junjou
they've gone into the summer fire
natsu no hi ni tobikonda
the fireflies aren't coming back
hotaru wa kaeranai
you didn't say a single word and left a kiss for me behind
anata wa nanimo iwazu kuchizuke wo nokoshite
and nodded as you still got burned
kitsuzuku mama unazuita ne
it was so sad that my life was wavering
kanashii hodo inochi yurameiteita
sha la la some day in the future
sha la la itsuka kitto
I will for sure hold it in my hand
boku wa te ni suru nda
it will softly set ablaze
hakanaki mune ni sotto
a light in my empty heart
hikari moeteyuke
sha la la my sweet lovely dear
sha la la itoshiki hito
I can also see you right now
anata mo mieteiru no
the dazzling moon will softly
mabayui tsuki ga sotto
illuminate the morning day
ashita wo terashite
and strongly and strongly shine on
tsuyoku tsuyoku kagayaite
Tales of a Gutsy Ninja
- Jiraiya Ninja Scrolls - Part 1
There are two bells...
鈴は２つだ。
The fact that there are
only two bells means...
２つしかないってことは？
１人は 丸太か…。
(猿飛)察しがいいな 大蛇丸。
One person will lose...
You're very sharp, Orochimaru.
なぁ。 オレが鈴とったら
デートしてくれよ。
Say! If I get a bell,
you'll go out with me.
If you lose,
don't bother me anymore.
アンタが負けたら
もう つきまとわないで。
All right! I'll do it!
よっしゃ！ やったるで！
So many openings...
(自来也)スキだらけだぜ 今だ！
Now!
I won the bet, Jiraiya!
You get to go to the log.
自来也 アンタとの賭け
勝ったわね。
やっぱ アンタが丸太行き。
Shut up, flat-chested, chopping board Tsunade!
うるせえ！ 胸ペッタンコの
まな板綱手が！
What'd you say?!
You no-brained perv!
んだと コラ！
このインテリエロ助が!!
Now, now. That's enough...
はいはい もういいから。
Tsunade and Orochimaru may go.
綱手と大蛇丸は帰ってろ。
は～い。
フン。
Okay!
(猿飛)まったく お前は…。
You are hopeless...
How can a ninja keep falling
into such obvious traps?!
忍者が バレバレの罠に
何度も引っかかるとは 何事か！
Can't help it...
だって…。
Perhaps what you lack
is a purpose...
お前に足りないのは
目的かのぉ。
Huh?!
そうじゃのう…。
Let's see now...
おぉ あの手があるか。
Yes! We'll try this!
Wh-What?!
な 何だ!?
ま 慌てるな。 見ておれ。
Don't get so excited. Just watch.
Ninja Art: Summoning Jutsu!
忍法 口寄せ！
Awesome!
すげえ！
口寄せの術。
The Summoning Jutsu...
あらゆる生き物と
血で契約を交わしておき➡
You make a blood contract
with an animal,
and summon them at any time
using the Transportation Technique.
好きなとき 自在に忍術で呼び出す
時空間忍術じゃ。
I want to make a contract
with that one too!
オレも！
そいつと契約を結びたい！
そいつはムリじゃ。
That, you can't do.
Huh?
In the same way that every man
is destined to a different fate,
(猿飛)人の運命が
それぞれ違うように➡
so too is the animal to whom
he is intertwined.
契約できる生き物も
それぞれ 運命が決めてくれる。
Then which is my animal?
じゃあ
オレのはどいつだ？
契約の前に
もっと チャクラを練り➡
Before you can make a contract,
you need to be more adept
at molding chakra and sealing.
印の結び方を
勉強せねばならん。
え～っ また修業か…。
What? Not more training!
You will always find the answer
in your training!
コラ！ 修業の中に
答えはあるのじゃ！
＜目的をもった自来也は➡
Jiraiya had found a purpose
and from that day on,
he began taking
his training seriously. However...
その日から
マジメに修業を始めたが…＞
《もっと チャクラを練り➡
Mold more chakra...
印の結び方を勉強し…》
Study up on sealing...
時空間忍術を
マスターせねば！
I must master
the Transportation Technique...
Dammit!
この！
When will I be able to
make a contract?
いつになったら
契約できるんだ？
《オレ なんでこんな辛い修業を
してるんだ？》
Why do I put up with
this rough training?
If I were to have a boyfriend,
((彼氏にするんなら やっぱ
インテリエロ助より 大蛇丸かな))
I'd choose Orochimaru over
an no-brained perv like you.
The answer is simple!
答えは単純だ！
I just have to become
the ultimate ninja
最高の忍者になって 綱手のヤツを
振り向かせてみせるってこった！
and sweep Tsunade off her feet!
Now that that's settled,
there's no time to waste!
そうとなりゃあ
ジッとしてるヒマなんかねえ!!
ほぉ～！
Ah...
忍としての目的に 気がついたか！
So he's discovered his purpose
for becoming a ninja.
《綱手だけじゃねえ。
And not just Tsunade,
I'm gonna get all the pretty girls
to myself.
きれいな姉ちゃんを 独り占めだ！
えっと… チャクラを集中させて…。
Let's see...
Concentrate my chakra and...
the seal is boar, dog,
bird, monkey, sheep...
印は 亥 戌 酉 申 未…》
Wait! There's no telling
what will happen
待て！ 契約もせんで
時空間忍術を使っては➡
if you use the Transportation Technique
without making a contract first!
何が起こるか わからん！
Go!
いっけ～!!
うわぁ～っ!!
ここは…。
Where am I...?
んっ？
あいや 待たれい！
Hold it right there!
そのケンカ この自来也様が買った!!
I, the great Master Jiraiya,
shall take over this fight!
Heh! I guess that'll do!
ヘン！ ざっと こんなもんだ！
(ブン太)ふむ 人間の子じゃ。
Hmmm...
A human child.
Huh?! A-A talking toad!
えっ!? ガ… ガマが しゃべった！
And what about you?
そっちこそ 人間のくせに
ホントに 妙木山に来よってからに。
To think, a human would really
come to Mount Myoboku...
どういう意味だ？
What do you mean?!
フカサク様～！
Fukasaku-sama!
It's a human child.
人間の子でさぁ！
(フカサク)おぉ 現れたか。
Oh... so you've arrived.
You talk as though
you've been expecting me.
まるで オレが現れるのを
知ってたみたいだな。
あぁ 知っておった。
Yes, I knew you were coming.
The Great Lord Elder predicted it.
大じじ様の予言でな。
((この妙木山に
１人の人間の子が 迷い込む。
A human child will stumble
into Mount Myoboku,
and I will give that child the power
of the toad and a prophecy.
その子に ガマの力を与え
予言を与える。
それが
ワシが ワシ自身のために見た夢…。
That is the dream which
I dreamt of myself...
My very own prophecy.
(予言だったんじゃ))
その人間が オレだったら➡
If that human is me...
then what is my  prophecy?!
与えてくれる予言って 何なんだ？
さぁな ワシは知らん。
Well... I don't know.
知らんって…。
Don't know?
お前は ここで修業しながら➡
You must stay here and train,
and wait for
the Great Lord Elder's prophecy.
大じじ様の予言を待つのじゃ。
H-Hold it!
ちょっ… ちょっと待てよ！
I made up my mind
to become strong
せっかく 強くなって
女の子に モテモテになろうってのに！
so that I'll be popular with women...
カエルにモテても しようがないぜ！
There's no point in getting popular
with frogs!
つべこべ 言うでない！
Quit complaining!
This is your destiny.
これが お前の運命じゃけえ！
運命だって!?
あぁ。
My destiny?!
Yes. You managed to come
to Mount Myoboku.
この妙木山に来ることができた。
これ すなわち➡
This is proof that you were indeed
the chosen one.
お前が
選ばれた運命の子という証拠だ！
《選ばれた人間か…。
The chosen one, eh?
ここで修業して
強くなるってのも➡
Training here and becoming strong...
That's pretty tempting too.
結構 捨てがたいかもしれないな》
From this day forward,
Jiraiya divided his time between
＜ それ以来 自来也は
ガマの里 妙木山と➡
Mount Myoboku, the land of toads,
and the Hidden Leaf Village...
木ノ葉隠れの里を
行き来しながら➡
He spent the days of his youth
in both Sage and ninjutsu training.
仙人と忍術の修業を積む
少年時代を過ごしていった＞
＜ しかし それは➡
However...
It was not to be as simple as
Jiraiya had thought.
自来也が考えていたほど
甘いものではなかった＞
《ここへ来て
確かに ワシは強くなった。
I've definitely gotten stronger
since coming here.
でも…。
But...
Tsunade is as cold as ever.
相変わらず 綱手は冷たい…。
Not just that...
いや… そもそも選ばれた運命を
持つ人間の目的が➡
If I was destined to be
the chosen one,
should my purpose simply
be to impress a girl?
女の子に
モテることだけでいいのか…。
それだけのために
ワシは強くなろうとしているのか》
Is that the only reason why
I'm trying to become strong?
Jiraiya! Jiraiya!
(ブン太)自来也！ 自来也！
Yeah?
おう！
自来也。 大じじ様が呼んじょる。
Jiraiya, the Great Lord Elder
has summoned you.
大ガマ仙人が？
はよ 行け。
The Great Lord Elder...?
Hurry up.
He has seen your prophecy!
お前への予言が出とんじゃ！
For real, Bunta?!
それ ホントか！ ブン太！
As summoned.
(自来也)お呼びで。
おぉ。
Ah, good. I'm glad you've come!
よう来た よう来た。
Huh?
え？ 誰だったかいの？
Who're you again?
大じじ様。
自来也ですじゃ 自来也！
Great Lord Elder, it's Jiraiya!
This is Jiraiya!
Oh, that's right! Right!
My, how you've grown...
おぉ… そうじゃった
そうじゃった。
大きゅうなったのぉ…。
Gah, you're the one who summoned him,
ya great senile old geezer!
(シマ)ったく
自分で呼んだくせにのぉ。
この大ボケじじいが！
母ちゃん。
Senile old geezer?!
Ma, how dare ya call
the Great Lord Elder a senile old geezer!
大じじ様に向かって
大ボケじじいとは何じゃ！
大ボケじじいとは！
コラ コラ ケンカはいけん。
Now now, let's not fight.
Spouses oughta get along...
夫婦は 仲ような。
By the way...
ところで そこの…
誰じゃったかいの？
Who're you, again?
自来也ちゃんよ… 大じじ様は➡
Jiraiya-chan.
The Great Lord Elder had
a dream about you.
お前の夢を見られたんじゃ。
As you are aware,
it is a prophecy.
お前も知ってのとおり
これは予言じゃ。
心して聞け。
はい。
So listen carefully.
Yes, sir!
では伝える… ワシの夢では➡
I shall now tell you.
In my dream...
you, who are solely pervy, will still
manage to become a splendid ninja.
エロいだけのお主も
いずれ 立派な忍になる。
And in time, you will have
your own disciple...
そして 一人前に
弟子を持つことになるのじゃが…。
《エロいだけって…
そういうことは➡
Solely pervy...?
Can't believe he remembers
that particular detail...
しっかり覚えてんだから ったく》
その弟子は 将来➡
That disciple will become a ninja
who will bring about a great change
忍の世に
大きな変革をもたらす忍になる。
to the ninja world.
That is what I saw in my dream.
夢では そう見えた。
変革？
A great change?
Either great stability
or great destruction.
世に それまでにない
安定をもたらすか…。
The likes of which this world
has never seen before.
破滅をもたらすか…
その どちらかの変革じゃ。
One of those two.
どちらかって…
どういうことですか？
One of those two?
What does that mean?
お主は その変革者を導く者じゃ。
You will guide that revolutionary.
The day will come when you will
be forced to make a critical selection.
いずれ お主には大きな選択を
迫られる時が来るじゃろう。
選択？
Selection?
その選択次第で 世の変革が➡
Your choice shall decide
which way the change goes.
どちらに転ぶか
決まってしまうのじゃ。
What must I do...?
In order to make the right choice?
ワシは… どうすればいいんですか？
正しく選択するには…。
In my dream, you traveled the world,
writing books.
夢では 世界を歩いて
本を書いておったのぉ。
本？ なんで また…。
Books? Whatever for?
I do not know either.
ワシにも 理由はわからんがの…。
Perhaps it will be a journey
around the world
世界をめぐり 森羅万象を見て回る
ということじゃろうか。
to see all things in nature.
大じじ様の予言…
今までに はずれたことは？
Great Lord Elder, have your prophecies
ever not come to pass?
No, never.
ないのぉ…。
自来也。 いよいよ旅へ出るんか？
Jiraiya, you are leaving?
Yup!
おぉ。 今のワシじゃ
変革者を導くことなんてできん。
At this point in my life,
there's no way I can guide someone
who will be a revolutionary...
Let alone make the right choice.
ましてや 正しい選択なんて
できるわけがない…。
Hmm...
ふむ…。
もっと いろんなことを見て➡
I guess I need more time
to see many more things,
いろんな人と
出会う時間が必要なようじゃ。
and meet different people.
I see...
そうか…。
Just like in
the Great Lord Elder's dream,
まずは 大じじ様の
夢のままに世界を歩いて➡
I shall journey throughout the world
and perhaps, write a book.
本でも書くことにするさ。
It seems that is my destiny.
それが ワシの運命らしいからな。
＜自来也が
大ガマ仙人の夢の意味を求めて➡
While Jiraiya journeyed and
searched for the meaning
behind the Great Lord Elder's dream,
放浪の旅をしている頃➡
the state of the world grew
steadily more chaotic.
世の中は
次第に騒がしくなっていった。
The peace that had prevailed among
the Five Great Nations became fragile.
忍五大国の統治による
平穏も危うくなり➡
Aggression between lands
increased as did internal strife,
その揺らぎは
各国に侵略や内乱を呼び起こし➡
and the people began to suffer.
人々の生活をも脅かし始めた＞
お若いの なんで旅をしておる？
Young man...
Why are you traveling?
I'm searching for my destiny.
自分の運命を探してるんだ。
Oh...?
ほう。
ある方が見た夢のままに➡
Someone saw me in a dream.
And just like in that dream,
I journey from land to land.
世界を歩いている。
Oh my, what's the matter...?
おぉ どうした？
Here, have one. It's milk candy.
ひとつどうじゃ 乳アメじゃ。
A puppet?
傀儡？
ほう この子が言うておる。
Oh, this child tells me...
Destiny is not something you search for!
運命は探すものではない。
やってきた運命に
のっかるものだとな。
Destiny is something you latch onto
when it presents itself.
The age of war is coming.
戦乱のときが迫っておる。
Mechanical skills are useless
in times of peace,
平和なときには
役に立たぬカラクリの技も➡
but some feudal lord may pay
a high price for my services.
どこかの大名に
高く売れるかもしれん。
So he is a ninja too...
《あやつも また忍か…。
He has chosen to ride the wave
to the age of destruction.
ヤツは破滅の時代の波にのることを
選択したんだのぉ。
But that will only...
しかし それでは…》
Let's have more fun.
もっと楽しみましょうよ。
Come on.
ねぇ。
う～ん…。
Mmmm...
What are you writing?
何を書いてるの？
Just scribbling...
that riding on the wave of the times
時代の波にのるだけじゃ➡
will not result in the revolutionary
change needed for peace.
この世を今までなかったような➡
平和にするための変革は
ムリだってことをな…。
Say, say! If you're gonna
change something, change me!
ねぇねぇ
変えるなら私を変えてよ。
I suppose you're right.
That does sound more fun.
そうだのぉ
そのほうが楽しそうだ。
This is fraud!
≪こんなのイカサマだ！
こんなもんにカネなんか払えるか！
As if I'll pay for something like this!
Hold it right there!
あいや 待たれい！
I shall take over this fight!
このケンカ ワシが買った!!
Damn it!
クソッ！ 何て ひでえ運命だ。
How can fate be so cruel?!
I worked hard on cultivating the land
with what little knowledge I had.
一族復興のために
慣れぬクワを手に➡
All for the sake of my clan, and yet...
畑を耕してきたというのに。
So this fellow is dissatisfied with
the way the world is going...
《コイツ 今の世の流れに
不満を持っておるのか…》
Have a drink...
どうだ 一献。
I've been searching for
my destiny too, but it's very elusive.
ワシも自分の運命を
探しておるのだが➡
なかなか見つからん。
Humph... It's useless to search
for something like that.
フン… そんなもん探してもムダさ。
My people have no chance
オレたち一族だけじゃ
大国の忍里にゃ➡
against the ninja villages
of the Great Nations...
太刀打ちできねえ…。
This guy...
Is that all he can do... complain?
《何だ コイツ
グチを言っとるだけかい》
You are wrong...
それは違うぞ。
うん？
Huh?
I teach children in a village...
ボクは ある里で
子供たちを教えている。
about how to fight back
when faced with a harsh fate.
困難な運命に向き合ったとき
どう対処すべきか。
その方法を…。
So education could end a war?
教育で戦が止められるってのか。
きれい事を言うんじゃねえ！
Cut the pretty talk!
What?!
何!?
《こやつも忍!?》
Is he a ninja too?
それはムリだな。
だが よりよき選択肢を選ぶ力を➡
No, that it cannot...
However, perhaps I can
teach them skills
that enable them
to make better choices.
身につけさせることは
できるかもしれん。
お主に問う。 その選択肢とは？
Let me ask you...
What are those choices?
Life or death...
Those are the choices.
死ぬか生きるかの選択肢よ。
ボクに教えられるのは
生き残るための方法だけだ。
The only thing I can teach them
is how to survive.
That's not good enough.
《それだけでは ダメなんだ。
I must choose the revolutionary
who will bring peace to the world.
ワシは この世に
平和をなせる変革者を➡
選ばねばならない…》
To bring destruction upon this world.
この世に破滅をもたらすか➡
Or to bring about a peace which
we have never known before...
今までなかったような
平和に導くか。
That depends on the commitment
of each and every person!
それは 皆の心がけ次第だ！
Hmm... Could this person be...?
《ほう コイツ ひょっとして…》
Say, you!
お主！
You just might be the person
I've been looking for!
ひょっとして
ワシの探している人間かもしれん！
ほう。
Oh...?
What would you do in order
to bring peace to this world?
この世を平和に導くには
どうする？
The world is heading towards
an age of war and strife...
世は戦乱に向かって
動き始めたのだ。
もう止められん。
There's no stopping it.
You just said it depends on
each person's commitment, didn't you?
でも今 心がけ次第と。
どうやれば
この人たちの運命が変わるのだ？
How do we change
these people's destinies?
ただ ひたすら祈りなされ。
Just pray hard.
That is all men can do.
人にできることは それしかない。
《フン…
やはり この男も違ったか》
This man is not the one... either.
今のは!?
What was that?!
これは普通の人たちが住む村。
なぜ忍が!?
This is just an ordinary village!
Why would a ninja...?!
This shuriken jutsu...
その手裏剣術… お前 風魔だな!?
You are from the Fuma, aren't you?!
Why attack people who
are living in peace?!
なぜ
平穏に暮らす人々の村を襲う！
You are also a ninja.
お前も忍だろ。
I am journeying in search of the one
who will become my disciple.
(自来也)弟子とするべき男と
出会うため旅をしている。
Humph! Why waste time
on such a tedious thing?!
フン！ 何を悠長なことを。
The balance of power between
lands has become shaky
今や各国のバランスは崩れ➡
and we are on the verge of
a great war...
いつ大戦に発展しても
おかしくないという この時期に。
あの村も 忍が潜入しているという
情報のもと潰されたのだ。
That village was also destroyed due
to a tip that ninja had infiltrated it.
ただ それだけでか!?
Just because of a tip?!
潰さなければ潰される。
It's destroy, or be destroyed.
ためらったものは
やられる世の中だ。
We live in a world where
you'll die if you hesitate!
《煙玉か！》
A Smoke Bomb!
(自来也)うわっ！ うっ…。
なかなかやるのぉ。
You're pretty good.
お前も忍なら
見逃すことはできぬ。
If you are a ninja too,
I cannot let you live.
あきらめろ！
これがオレたち 忍の運命だ。
Just give up...
This is our fate as ninja.
Can I say something?
ひと言 いいか？
I don't feel like listening...
聞く気はねえ。 もう くたばれ!!
Just... die!
Give up...
ワシが あきらめるのを…。
...on me giving up!
あきらめろ。
クッ…。
オレを倒しても
また次の刺客が村を襲う。
Even if you bring me down,
another assassin will attack
the village...
As long as we are cursed to live
in this ninja world,
オレたちが 呪われた忍の世界に
生きている限り➡
there will be no peace.
平穏はないぞ。
The Great Toad Sage's
prophecy said that I am destined
《ガマ仙人は ワシが➡
to train the revolutionary
who will bring peace to this world.
この世に平和をもたらす
変革者を育てることを予言した。
しかし ワシはまだ➡
However, I haven't even encountered
this disciple.
その運命の弟子にも
会えずにいる…》
＜ すでに このとき➡
Already at this time,
battles were inevitably being fought.
止めようもない
戦いの連鎖が起こっていた。
Jiraiya was also forced to take
a short break from his journey
自来也もまた
運命と出会う旅を しばし休み➡
and returned to the Hidden Leaf Village.
木ノ葉の里に
戻らねばならなかった＞
戦争だからね 今は。
We're at war... after all.
Orochimaru...
大蛇丸…。
《忍の世から
こんな悲しみをなくすためには➡
In order to erase this sadness
from the ninja world...
I must find the revolutionary...
ワシが変革者を見つけねば。
I must choose the one
who will bring peace.
平和な世を作る者を
選択せねばならんのだ》
The flames of war finally drew
in Jiraiya and his comrades.
＜戦いの炎は
ついに自来也たちまで➡
その渦に いやおうもなく
巻き込むことになる。
This would come to be known
as the Third Great Ninja War.
これが 後の第三次忍界大戦と
呼ばれる戦いである。
自来也たちが
伝説の三忍と呼ばれるのは➡
Shortly afterwards, the three
would come to be known
as the "Legendary Sannin".
これより
しばらくしてのことである＞
keep your pants and shirt on even if you're unable to do it right now
ima dekinakute mo aseranaide awatenaide
you should believe in yourself and take it at your own pace
kimi no mai peesu de jibun shinjite yukkuri ikeba ii
life always throws you curveballs and the reason of that is
yo kono yo wa hitosujinawa de ikanai sore wa naze nara
it's a test made by God so that's why it's quite hard
kamisama ga tsukutta tesuto dakara muzukashii nda
arts? science? or rather how about ethics?
bunkei rikei mushiro doutoku kimi nara kore wo dou toku
this is just like life so put your heart and soul into seriousness
kore wa maru de jinsei dakara uchikomu shinken ni
we worry ourselves lose ourselves and we keep asking ourselves questions
bokura wa nayamu mayou nandomo jibun ni toikakeru
we aren't one and relentesly persue our search for answers
hitotsu ja nai kotae sagashi gamushara ni oikakeru
keep your pants and shirt on even if you're unable to do it right now
ima dekinakute mo aseranaide awatenaide
you should believe in yourself and take it at your own pace
kimi no mai peesu de jibun shinjite yukkuri ikeba ii
the current me would tell me that if I was from the future
mirai no bokura nara ima no boku ni oshiete agerareru
you should keep pursuing it until your efforts change yourself
kimi no doryoku ga jishin ni kawaru toki made oitsuzukereba ii
Next Episode
Boy, it's not easy coming up with
ideas for writing a book.
The main hero of this book has
seen too much of the ninja world,
(ナツ)『FAIRY TAIL』 前回までは…。
where battle brings
further battle.
(ルーシィ)いつのまにか
カナとはぐれた私は➡
It's a world filled with hate.
七眷属の
華院ヒカルと戦うことになったの。
I want him to somehow
wipe away the hate
(ハッピー)おいらとナツは 途中から
参戦することになったけど➡
and create a world of peace, yet...
ナツは いいとこなかったね。
うっせえ！
Aaah! It's so hard to build up
a story to the climax!
でも その場でひらめいた
新必殺技で➡
What shall I do?!
白だんごをとっちめたぞ！
必殺技ねぇ…。
Next time:
"Tales of a Gutsy Ninja - Jiraiya Ninja Scrolls - Part 2"
Tales of a Gutsy Ninja
- Jiraiya Ninja Scrolls - Part 2